Masaryk Publications Trust mss., 1958-1989 LMC 2369
Lilly Library
Masaryk Publications Trust mss.
1958-1989
Lilly Library
Masaryk, Alice Garrigue, 1879-1966
Masaryk, T. G. (Tomáš Garrigue), 1850-1937
LMC 2369
3 Boxes 3 standard
The Masaryk Publications Trust mss., 1958-1989, consists of the papers of the Masaryk Publications Trust from the time of its formation until its termination.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 1990
Historical Note
The Masaryk Publications Trust was a small non-profit trust founded in 1960 by Alice Garrigue Masaryk and her sister Olga Masaryk Revilliod for the purpose of spreading "as widely as possible the knowledge of the principles which Thomas G. Masaryk (their father and the first president of Czechoslovakia) considered essential for a social and progressive democracy." The press published several of Thomas G. Masaryk's books and related literature, including Alice Masaryk's memoir Dětství a mládí (Childhood and Youth).
Scope and Content Note
This collection includes financial records, materials relating to book publications, correspondence, including those from John Tabor, and minutes of meetings of the Trustees.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in original order.
Related Materials
See Masaryk mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
See Masaryk mss. II, also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Slavs; České Budějovice (Czech Republic); Czech literature; Publishers and publishing
- Correspondence (Box 1)
- Contributors
  - Miscellaneous Contributions, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Dr. George A. Kelley, 1963-1969 (Box 1)
  - Mabel L. Gillespie (Box 1)
  - Dr. Richard Stunt, 1963-1969 (Box 1)
- Masaryk and Alice Publications Trust (Box 1)
- David Ketter Income Tax Exemptions, 1963-1969 (Box 1)
- Financial Files (Box 1)
- Receipts and Expenditures Books, 1963-1978 (Box 1)
- Draft Minutes and Receipts (Box 1)
- Financial Statements, Meeting Minutes (Box 1)
- David Ketter Income Tax Exemptions, 1970-1977 (Box 1)
- RCM Bills and Receipts, 1978 (Box 1)
- Friendship Fund Tax Exemption, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
- Tax Returns (Box 1)
- Royalties and Special Expenditures (Box 1)
- Jan Papanak Correspondence Treasurer (Box 1)
- Financial Statements, 1978-1989 (Box 1)
- Ruth and Mitchell AGM Book (Box 1)
- George Gibian, 1982 (Box 1)
- Annual Financial Statements, 1967-1978 (Box 1)
- Statements, 1978-1989 (Box 1)
- Miller Hebrew RFE AGM, 1960 (Box 1)
- Financial Statements, 1960-1968 (Box 1)
- Mellon Bank Statements and Mellon Bank Canceled Checks
  - 1960 (Box 1)
  - 1961 (Box 1)
  - 1962 (Box 1)
  - 1964 (Box 1)
  - 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 1)
  - Paid Bills, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - Checking Account Statements, 1969-1978 (Box 1)
  - Mellon Bank Checks and Balances Book (Box 1)
- Mrs. Jan Lowenbach (Box 1)
- Chapter VII In Exile from Hitler 39-45 Copy for Mrs. Papanek (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Documents (Box 2)
- Minute Book (Box 2)
- Agreement of May 11, 59 And Amendments, 1959-1964 (Box 2)
- Vol. III. Spirit of Russia History of Manuscript (Box 2)
- George Gibian Prague Visit, 1969 (Box 2)
- Financial Statements (Box 2)
- John K. Tabor, 1958-1960 (Box 2)
- Opinions of Scholars (Box 2)
- Empowering Documents (Box 2)
- Reavis and McGrath Correspondence (1/2) (Box 2)
- Reavis and McGrath Correspondence (2/2) (Box 2)
- Personnel 4/6/63-1/30/64 (Box 2)
- Department of Internal Affairs/Commerce John K. Tabor (Box 2)
- Papers to Storage (Box 2)
- Termination (Box 2)
- Tabor to MPT Facts from Files by Date (Box 2)
- Law and Statutes (Box 2)
- Termination Materials (Copies) (Box 2)
- Tabor Correspondence
  - 1962-1966 (Box 2)
  - 1963-1967 (Box 2)
  - 1980 (Box 2)
  - 1984 (Box 2)
  - 1988 (Box 2)
- General Legal Services
  - Correspondence, 1984-3-11-1984-7-6 (Box 3)
  - John K. Tabor Deed of Trust, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Tabor Trust Correspondence, 1959-1968 (Box 3)
  - Charles Evan New York City Translation Royalty Rights, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Thomas W. Pomeroy, Jr., 1965-1969 (Box 3)
  - David Ketter General Correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box 3)
- Granddaughter Waivers
  - David Ketter Royalty Waivers Granddaughters T.G. Masaryk, 1975 (Box 3)
  - David Ketter General Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Anna Masaryk Power of Attorney, Waiver, 1972-1975 (Box 3)